Joon Sik Kim

Last Updated: May 14, 2023

July 2014 - Nov 2014

I recently graduated from CMU with a PhD in machine learning. My research focuses on methods that can assist our understanding of complex machine learning models, and their application to useful downstream tasks involving human users. Methods include efficient decomposition of neural network predictions, algorithmic fairness assessments; applications include dataset debugging, spurious correlation detection, and assisting human users in document matching. Primarily focused on deep learning models applied to text and image data, the approaches studied include model-agnostic perspectives that can be extended to different data modalities.

CONTACT

Email: davidkim21c@gmail.com
Website: https://wnstlr.github.io

Undergraduate Research Student for Dr. Vasumathi Raman

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University	Pittsburgh, PA
Doctor of Philosophy, Machine Learning	May 2023
Thesis: Methods and Applications of Explainable Machine Learning	
A 1 · A · (TD 1 11	

Advisor: Ameet Talwalkar

Carnegie Mellon University	Pittsburgh, PA
Master of Science, Machine Learning (GPA 3.86/4.00)	May 2020

California Institute of Technology Bachelor of Science, Computer Science (GPA 4.0/4.3) Pasadena, CA June 2017

EXPERIENCE

Microsoft Research Summer Research Intern	Redmond, WA June 2021 - Aug 2021
J.P.Morgan Summer Intern at AI Research	New York, NY May 2019 - Aug 2019
SK Inc. Machine Learning Research Intern	Seoul, South Korea June 2017 - Aug 2017

Computer Vision Lab, California Institute of Technology	Pasadena, CA
Undergraduate Research Student for Prof. Pietro Perona	July 2016 - Dec 2016

endergraduate liesedaren stadent fer 1 reg. 1 tetro 1 erend	July 2010 Bee 2010
California Institute of Technology Undergraduate Research Student for Prof. Yisong Yue	Pasadena, CA June 2015 - June 2016
California Institute of Technology	Pasadena, CA

Criminal Investigation Command, Ministry of National Defense	Seoul, South Korea
Soldier, Software Developer, Interpreter	Oct 2012 – July 2014

Laser Interferometer Gravitational-wave Observatory (LIGO)	Pasadena, CA
Undergraduate Research Student for Dr. Parameswaran Ajith	Jan 2012 - Aug 2012

PUBLICATIONS¹

- 8. Keegan Harris, Valerie Chen, **Joon Sik Kim**, Ameet Talwalkar, Hoda Heidari, Steven Wu. *Bayesian Persuasion for Algorithmic Recourse*. Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022.
- 7. **Joon Sik Kim**, Gregory Plumb, Ameet Talwalkar. Sanity Simulations for Saliency Methods. International Conference on Machine Leaning (ICML), 2022. (Spotlight)
- 6. Valerie Chen*, Jeffrey Li*, **Joon Sik Kim****, Gregory Plumb**, Ameet Talwalkar. *Interpretable Machine Learning: Moving From Mythos to Diagnostics*. ACM Queue 19.6 (2022): 28-56.
- Kwangho Kim, Jisu Kim, Manzil Zaheer, Joon Sik Kim, Frederic Chazal, Larry Wasserman. PLLay: Efficient Topological Layer based on Persistence Landscapes. Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020.
- 4. **Joon Sik Kim**, Jiahao Chen, Ameet Talwalkar. *FACT: A Diagnostic for Group Fairness Trade-offs*. International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2020.
- 3. David I. Inouye, Leqi Liu, **Joon Sik Kim**, Bryon Aragam, Pradeep Ravikumar. *Automated Dependence Plots*. Uncertainty in Artificiail Intelligence (UAI), 2020.
- 2. Chih-Kuan Yeh*, **Joon Sik Kim***, Ian E.H. Yen, Pradeep Ravikumar. Representer Point Selection for Explaining Deep Neural Networks. Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2018.
- 1. Matteo Ruggero Ronchi, **Joon Sik Kim**, Yisong Yue. A Rotation Invariant Latent Factor Model for Moveme Discovery from Static Poses. IEEE International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM), 2016.

PRE-PRINTS

- 2. **Joon Sik Kim**, Valerie Chen, Danish Pruthi, Nihar Shah, Ameet Talwalkar. *Assisting Human Decisions in Document Matching*. arXiv 2023.
- Valerie Chen, Muyu Yang, Wenbo Cui, Joon Sik Kim, Ameet Talwalkar, Jian Ma. Best Practices for Interpretable Machine Learning in Computational Biology. bioRxiv 2022.10.28.513978

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Reviewer (FAccT 2023, ICML 2022, FAccT 2022, ICML 2021); Program Committee (Workshop on Fair AI in Finance, NeurIPS 2020).

FELLOWSHIPS, AWARDS

Kwanjeong Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship	2017 - 2021
Caltech Bhansali Family Prize in Computer Science	2017
Caltech CMS Celebration of Undergraduate Research Best Demo/Poster Award	2015
Caltech Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship	2014, 2015, 2016
Caltech Physics 11 Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship	2012

TEACHING

10-725 Convex Optimization (Carnegie Mellon University)

Spring 2023
10-737 Creative AI (Carnegie Mellon University)

Fall 2019

 $^{^{1*}}$ indicates equal contribution; includes conference workshop papers